Up to this point, I've only been using the center camera
到目前为止 我只用了中央摄像头的图像
image, but now it might be helpful to use side camera
其实两侧摄像头的图像
images for training, too.
在训练时也可能很有帮助
Using the side camera images carries two benefits.
使用两侧摄像头的图像有两大好处
One, it's simply more data.
其一 可以提供更多训练数据
In fact, it's three times as much data.
实际上 数据量是原来的三倍
The other benefit is that using these images
其二 使用这些图像
will help teach the network how to steer back to the center
可以帮助我们教会网络
if the vehicle starts drifting off to the side.
当车辆开始向路缘偏移时如何转向以回到道路中央
Let's look at the left image.
我们看一下左侧摄像头的图像
This image is a little off to the left side of the road,
从这张图看 车有点向道路左侧偏移
but it's paired with a steering measurement of zero.
但它的转向值为 0
That's because when this image was taken,
这是因为图像拍摄时
the center of the vehicle really was in the center of the road.
车辆中心实际上位于道路中心
So how do I use this image?
那么 我们如何使用这张图像呢？
Basically, I want to train the network
实际上 我想教会神经网络
to steer a little harder to the right
在看到一幅这样的图像时
whenever the network sees an image like this.
都向右稍稍多转向一点
I'll do this by taking the actual steering
具体方式是 取实际的转向值
measurement, which in this case is zero,
比如这个图像对应为 0
and adding a small correction factor to it.
然后对其增加一个很小的校正系数
I could actually draw out a model
其实我可以画出模型
and use trigonometry and physics to calculate
并使用三角法和物理学方法计算出
an optimal correction factor, but I'm just
最优校正系数 但在这里请允许我稍微偷一下懒
going to be lazy and try a correction factor of 0.2.
简单地把 0.2 作为校正系数
Similarly, for the right camera image,
类似地 对于右摄像头的图像
I'm going to train the network to steer a little harder
我准备教会网络
to the left.
都向左稍稍多转向一点
I'll do that by subtracting the correction factor
具体方式是 每次使用右侧摄像头图像时
from the actual steering measurement
都从实际的转向角中
whenever I use a right camera image.
减去校正系数
I implement this by looping through the first three
要对所有训练数据使用这个系数
tokens of each line in the CSV file,
我需要遍历 CSV 文件中每一行的前三列内容
and I use these to load each camera image into the images
而后把每幅图像
array.
加载到训练图像矩阵中
Then I add three measurements to the measurements array
然后 我把三项校正后的测量数据
corresponding to each image I just added.
添加到每幅图像对应的测量阵列中
Now I should have three times as much data,
现在的训练数据是原先的三倍
and my model should perform better.
模型的驾驶表现应该更完善了
Let's see.
我们看看事实上究竟如何
It looks like the model is indeed
从训练过程看起来的确是这样
training on three times as many camera images.
训练用的图像数量是原来的三倍
I'm excited to see how well this drives.
我已经迫不及待地想看它的驾驶表现了
Ooh, it looks like it drives worse.
啊哦 看起来反而更糟糕了
It's just pulling to the left.
它一直在左转